Ing. Roman Ožana / Resume

Hi there,

my name is Roman Ožana. I am a freelance webdesigner and developer with more than 13 years of experiences. I'm here to create websites and applications easy to use, intuitive and modern inside. I love tech startups and community around. Enjoy working in small and effective team.

Address: Prague, Přímětická st.

Web: https://ozana.cz
Email: roman@ozana.cz

Phone: +420 605 783 455

Twitter: @OzzyCzech



Work Experiences

Testomato s.r.o. – Co-founder & lead developer

10 years 21 days

March 2012 - present

Work as full time Javascript and PHP lead developer.

Devel.cz Lab s.r.o. - PHP/JS developer

10 years 10 months 22 days

October 2009 - present

Work as experienced PHP and Javascript developer mostly on zdrojak.cz.

Freelance web designer

13 years 1 month 22 days

October 2009 - present

Freelance web designer and developer of Internet application – mostly in PHP and Javascript.

Former Work Experiences

Intergraph s.r.o. – Application Engineer

9 months

July 2010 - April 2011

Application Engineer (external consultant) – testing of corporate solution for metadata sharing and managing. Developing of simple C# .NET applications.

Skvely.CZ s.r.o. – PHP developer

1 year 5 months

March 2009 - July 2010

Works there as web application developer mostly in PHP and developing some modules for e-commerce Magento.

Skills & Technologies

Day-to-day comfort

- PHP
- OOP, DI, IOC, design patterns
- SQL language (MariaDB, MySQL)
- · MongoDB, Redis, Memcached
- Javascript ES6
- · React, Angular, jQuery
- HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind (LESS, Sass, cssnext, PostCSS)
- Responsive Layout and Design
- · Webpack, Parcel, Makefile

Quality assurance

- E2E testing with Protractor
- Selenium + Selenium IDE
- Unit Testing (PHP Unit, Nette Tester, Mocha)

Experience with

- NextJS
- Node.js
- Gulp & Grunt
- Couchbase
- Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator

DevStack

- Docker
- Git
- · Webpack, Makefile, Bash
- Travis & GitLab CI
- MacOS and OS Linux

Languages

Czech – native language

English - communicative

Additional Info

Driving license: B

Education

VŠB – Technical University of Ostrava

2002 - 2007: Geoinformatics

- Study program: Geodesy and cartography, Geoinformatics
- Degree: Master's degree (Msc., Geoingormatics)
- Address: VŠB Technical university of Ostrava, 17. listopadu 15, Ostrava Poruba, Faculty of Mining and Geology

SPŠE Rožnov pod Radhoštěm

1997 – 2001: Electronic computer systems

